It would be great if the web was all plain text, but it's not.
So Flask provides something called templating, which allows us to quickly and easily access variables without having to use JavaScript or anything fancy.
In order to use a template, in which ever folder your hello.py is, we're going to open the terminal.
We can kill our server for now, just so we know we're on the right path.
We're going to make a new directory and we're going to call it templates.
And then we're going to touch a file here index.html.
And that touch command won't work for Windows.
So let me quickly.
Yeah, I believe it's FC and then a forward slash.
So for Windows, it's not a forward slash.
It's a bracket templates index.html.
To get our simple template to work, we have to do a few things.
The first is, we need to import render template from Flask.
And render template takes the name of the template that we want to use.
So here instead of returning hello world, we're going to return render template.
We're going to pass in the name of our template.
We don't have to put in the templates directory.
Now let's open our index.html file and put this is a template and save that.
After you've done creating the files, remember to run your Flask server again.
And now if I click on this link, there we go.
Got this is a template.
Is everyone seeing the same thing?
Flask supports a templating language called jinger.
That allows you to populate your HTML files with data from your Flask app at render time.
I'm not going to go into the specifics of jinger, but I will show you.
A simple example.
So let's just make a, let's put some HTML tags in our template.
And make the title of our page B hello from Flask.
We can delete our, this is a template.
So in order for our template to have variables, we need to explicitly pass them in.
The way that we would do that is via this render template.
So the first argument is the name of the template.
And then any other arguments after that get passed into the template.
So I can say the name is nina and then pass it in here in the call to render template.
Going back to our template file, we now have access to this variable.
And so this jinger templating language looks like this.
The arguments are within a curly brace percent sign.
So if you use templating for other languages like JavaScript, this shouldn't look too far fetched.
And so I can put simple expressions in here.
If you want to know more about jinger, I would check out the documentation.
But I can say if name.
And with jinger, jinger is just like each channel.
So we need to have opening tags and closing tags to signify a block of code.
So to close an if statement in jinger, you would just say end of.
Now we can put some conditional code between these two tags.
I can say hello in h1.
And then to access the value of a variable, you just use two sets of curly braces.
And this will print out the value of name.
Let's reload our web page.
And we'll see the information from our new template.
Does everyone see that?
Great.
So just a little bit more about flask, like I mentioned, flask.
Any of these other web frameworks, they're really easy to add to.
So if your app is ready for the big time and you want to add.
Database that flask is a useful mechanism for accessing database objects.
It makes it really easy to use databases and store your data for a dynamic web app.
You can find a lot more information about that in the flask documentation.
But unless you want to be here until midnight, it's a topic for another day.
In terms of deploying your web app, there are.
There are a lot of different options from beginner to advanced.
To deploy to our real web server.
I think Haroku is the best bet for beginners.
It's pretty easy.
It's a lot of stuff by stuff instructions.
And then as your app grows, you can graduate from there.
The flask documentation lists other deployment options.
And know that we're covering just the basics of flask today.
But to deep dive and learn more.
The flask mega tutorial is a great resource to check out after this class.
And say huge tutorial that covers everything from databases to.
Oh off to time zones.
Probably take you a few days to complete.
And you'll feel pretty comfortable with flask after that.